Guide to the Fred Friendly Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Fred Friendly Papers,
1917-2004
[Bulk Dates: 1950-1990]
Friendly, Fred W.
97.4 linear feet (220 document boxes, 3 index card boxes, 2 record cartons, 1 oversized box).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
6297812
This collection encompasses the life and career of Fred Friendly as an author, educator, and television news producer.
Biographical Note
Fred Friendly (1915-1998) was born Ferdinand Friendly Wachenheimer in Manhattan, New York. Son of Samuel Wachenheimer, a jewelry manufacturer, and Therese Friendly Wachenheimer, he lived in New York until the family moved to Providence, Rhode Island in 1926. He graduated from Hope Street High School and then attended Nichols Junior College in Massachusetts, where he graduated with an associate's degree in 1936.
Wachenheimer began his broadcast career as a radio announcer in Providence, where he took his mother's maiden name and was thereafter known as Fred Friendly. He wrote and narrated a program on WEAN called "Footprints in the Sands of Time", a short radio documentary program that profiled historic persons.
Friendly served in the Army during World War II and worked as a correspondent for "CBI Roundup", an Army newspaper for the China-Burma-India Theater. He was present at the liberation of the Malthausen concentration camp in Austria. Following Victory in Europe Day (May 7, 1945) he was granted a three-month leave of absence to travel in Europe. There, he experimented with audiotape techniques while making a documentary about troops. While this documentary was never distributed, it taught him much about audio techniques and the power of original footage. By the time he was discharged in 1945, as a master sergeant, he had been awarded four battle stars, the Legion of Merit, and the Soldier's Medal, which he received after he rescued several persons from a dock fire in India.
Following the war, Friendly returned to New York City. He married Dorothy Greene, a researcher for Life magazine in 1947; they had three children and would later divorce. Friendly then began work on "I Can Hear It Now", the record album that provided an oral history of the years 1933 to 1945. The record used only original recordings, not recreations, and interspersed famous speeches by leaders with more personal touches. He convinced Edward R. Murrow, already a well-known voice, to narrate the album. Released in 1948, the album was more successful than anticipated and marked the beginning of their collaborative work.
In 1949 and 1950 Friendly created two successful radio series for NBC: "Who Said That?", a quiz show featuring panelists and topical news questions, and "The Quick and the Dead", a four-part documentary about the development of the atomic bomb. Friendly then left to join Murrow at CBS, where they worked on Hear It Now, a radio series based on their successful recording. Taking the leap into the new medium of television, they debuted "See It Now", which broke ground as a long-form news program. The program began as a half-hour show in 1951, but later expanded to an hour in 1953. Murrow was the face of the broadcast, while Friendly focused on production.
"See It Now" dealt with a wide variety of news-topics, but throughout 1953 and 1954 Murrow and Friendly created and broadcast several programs that concentrated on Senator Joseph McCarthy and his investigation of communists in America. The first show that raised the McCarthy issue was "The Case of Milo Radulovich, A0589839," broadcast in October 1953. Radulovich was an Air Force reservist who was discharged because of allegations of communism against his family members. Friendly would later state that they were actively looking for stories to better illuminate the methods of Senator McCarthy. With this in mind, they created the program, "Report on Senator Joseph R. McCarthy," broadcast in March 1954. It relied soley on footage of McCarthy in order to let his own words be the focus of the program. CBS did extensive customer surveys after this program ran and the barrage of phone calls and telegrams arrived were mainly in support of the program. As time went on, Friendly and Murrow produced many other provocative programs dealing with issues such as race and the tobacco industry. The show was cancelled in 1958 when both men became committed to other projects.
In 1960, Friendly became the executive producer of the news documentary program, "CBS Reports". The show had a large staff and was able to handle long and large-scale investigative reports. Friendly was appointed the president of CBS News in 1964. This was to be a short-lived position, as he resigned in 1966. His decision to show Senator Fulbright's hearings on American involvement in the Vietnam War in the United States Senate was over-ridden, and a re-run of "I Love Lucy" was broadcast instead. He resigned in protest.
After his resignation, Friendly was invited to work at the Ford Foundation as the adviser to the President on Communications. His plan to fund a public television network with the profits from a communications satellite paid for by commercial networks met with opposition, and was not put into place. However, the idea did spur Congress to pass the Public Broadcasting Act in 1967, which created the Public Broadcasting System (PBS). With his previous work still fresh in his mind, Friendly penned "Due to Circumstances Beyond Our Control", a memoir about his time at CBS.
In 1968, Friendly married Ruth Mark, a former schoolteacher and widow. Each having three children from previous marriages, they raised their six children together. He began teaching at Columbia University as the Edward R. Murrow Professor of Journalism the same year. Bringing more life experience than degrees to his teaching career, his time in the Journalism School at Columbia University had a lasting impact. He created and instituted the Summer Program in Broadcast and Print Journalism for Members of Minority Groups (later renamed the Michele Clark Fellowship Program for Minority Journalists), which ran from 1968 to 1974. In 1974, he began the Media and Society Seminars, a series of conferences and round-table discussions that brought lawyers, politicians, doctors, and journalists together to talk about ethical issues. These later evolved into "The Fred Friendly Seminars", which are still in production today under the auspices of Ruth Friendly.
In 1976 Friendly published "The Good Guys, the Bad Guys and the First Amendment", which dealt with the history of the Federal Communications Commission's Fairness Doctrine, a regulation which required networks to provide equal time for opposing opinions on issues presented during a public broadcast. Upon ending his time at the Ford Foundation in 1980, Friendly had more time to devote to his "Media and Society Seminars" and also to his private speaking engagements. In 1981 he published "Minnesota Rag: The Dramatic Story of the Landmark Supreme Court Case that Gave New Meaning to Freedom of the Press", which delved into an influential court case.
Springing from personal and professional interest, Friendly's final book "The Constitution, That Delicate Balance" was published in 1993 as a companion to two "Media and Society Seminar" series, "The Constitution, That Delicate Balance" (1984), and "That Delicate Balance II: Our Bill of Rights" (1991). For his many contributions to television, Fred Friendly was inducted into the Academy of Television Arts & Sciences Hall of Fame in 1994. He died in New York in 1998.
Scope and Content
This collection encompasses the life and career of Fred Friendly as an author, educator, and television news producer. The collection is comprised of correspondence, printed materials, invitations to events, awards, photographs and audio-visual materials of news programs. Also represented are administrative files and memos from his work at CBS, the Ford Foundation, and Columbia University.
Arrangement
Arranged in eight series:
Series I. Correspondence, 1960-1992
Series II. Writing, 1940-1996
Series III. Media and Society Seminars, 1974-1996
Series IV. Conferences and Seminars, 1962-1996
Series V. Television and Radio, 1947-1991
Series VI. General, 1934-2004
Series VII. Photographs, 1917-1990
Series VIII. Media, 1961-1991.
Subjects
CBS Radio Network.; CBS Records (Firm); CBS Television Network.; Columbia Broadcasting System, inc.; Columbia Broadcasting System, inc.--History.; Columbia College (New York, N.Y.)--Students.; Columbia University.--School of Journalism.; Columbia University--Students.; United States.--Federal Communications Commission.; Media and Society Seminars.; Friendly, Fred W.; Miller, Arthur Raphael, 1934-; Murrow, Edward R.; Authors, American.; Radio journalism--United States--History--20th century.; Journalists--Interviews.; Journalists--United States.; Radio--History.; Radio journalists.; Television--History.; Television programs.; World War, 1939-1945--Journalism, Military.; Periodicals; Photographs
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
One folder in box 189 has been restricted until 2051.
Acquisition
Ruth Freindly, Gift, 1999.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1960-1992
  The bulk of Friendly’s correspondence relates to the production of the Media and Society Seminars (MSS), a process which required frequent communication with film crews, editors, and participants. Invitations to potential panelists describe a seminar's theme and goals, while other letters contain proposals for future seminars or reflections on completed ones, discussions on editing film, or expressions of thanks after an especially successful panel. The series also includes conversations between Friendly and Columbia professors, usually concerning course content or guest speakers. Personal correspondence is less common, but appears occasionally in the form of short letters to friends.
  This series consists of three subseries, which represent different filing systems. However, the content of all three series is similar and overlapping, and information related to a particular event, person, or topic may be found in multiple subseries.
  - Subseries I.1: General, 1960-1992
    This subseries consists of letters and memos that were pulled from other parts of the collection and then grouped by the first letter of the correspondent's name or institution. As further alphabetical arrangement was not undertaken, researchers should examine all folders in each letter group.
    - A (Box 2-3)
    - B (Box 5-9)
    - C (Box 11-15)
    - D (Box 16-17)
    - E (Box 18-19)
    - F (Box 19-22)
    - G (Box 24-26)
    - H (Box 27-30)
    - I (Box 30-31)
    - J (Box 31)
    - K (Box 33-35)
    - L (Box 36-39)
    - M (Box 40-42)
    - N (Box 44)
    - O (Box 45)
    - P (Box 46-48)
    - Q (Box 48)
    - R (Box 49-51)
    - S (Box 53-59)
    - T (Box 59-60)
    - U (Box 61)
    - V (Box 61)
    - W (Box 63-65)
    - Y (Box 65)
    - Z (Box 65)
    - Correspondent Unknown (Box 65-66)
    - Invitations (Box 66)
    - Personal (Box 66-67)
    - Notes to Students and Fans (Box 67)
    - Ruth Friendly Correspondence (Box 67)
  - Subseries I.2: Chronological, 1970-1992
    Correspondence in this subseries retains its original order. Letters and memos were first grouped alphabetically and then filed chronologically.
    - A, 1976-1991 (Box 1-2)
    - B, 1975-1991 (Box 4-5)
    - C, 1976-1991 (Box 10-11)
    - D, 1976-1991 (Box 15)
    - E, 1975-1991 (Box 18)
    - F, 1975-1991 (Box 19-20)
    - G, 1975-1991 (Box 23-24)
    - H, 1975-1991 (Box 27)
    - I, 1975-1991 (Box 30)
    - J, 1975-1991 (Box 31)
    - K, 1977-1990 (Box 32-33)
    - L, 1976-1990 (Box 35)
    - M, 1975-1992 (Box 37-38)
    - N, 1975-1991 (Box 43)
    - O, 1975-1991 (Box 45)
    - P, 1975-1991 (Box 46)
    - R, 1977-1991 (Box 49)
    - S, 1970-1991 (Box 53-54)
    - T, 1975-1992 (Box 59)
    - U, 1984-1991 (Box 61)
    - V, 1984-1991 (Box 61)
    - W, 1975-1991 (Box 62)
  - Subseries I.3: Alphabetical, 1960-1992
    Friendly kept files of correspondence from individual colleagues, friends, and institutions which were arranged alphabetically by name. Please note that additional correspondence with these individuals may also be found in subseries I.1 and I.2
    - ACLU, 1985 (Box 1, Folder F.1)
    - ALCOA Foundation, 1984 (Box 1, Folder F.2)
    - Abrams, Floyd, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder F.3)
    - Academy for Educational Development, 1989 (Box 1, Folder F.4)
    - Action on Smoking and Health, 1969 (Box 1, Folder F.5)
    - Adams, Arlin, 1987 (Box 1, Folder F.6)
    - American Bar Association, 1986 (Box 1, Folder F.7)
    - American Judicial Society, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder F.8)
    - Anti-Defamation League, 1990 (Box 1, Folder F.9)
    - Associated Press, 1986 (Box 1, Folder F.10)
    - Avery, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder F.11)
    - Barrett, Edward, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder F.5)
    - Benjamin Franklin Memorial Board, 1990 (Box 3, Folder F.6)
    - Bernstein, Robert L., 1966-1988 (Box 3, Folder F.7)
    - Blackman, Harry A., 1985 (Box 3, Folder F.8)
    - Bonneville International Corporation, 1986 (Box 3, Folder F.9)
    - Bork, Robert H., 1987 (Box 3, Folder F.10)
    - Brand, Stanley, 1986 (Box 3, Folder F.11)
    - Brennen, William, 1986 (Box 3, Folder F.12)
    - Buckley, William Jr., 1981 (Box 4, Folder F.1)
    - Burger, William E., 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder F.2)
    - Burnett, Carol, 1981 (Box 4, Folder F.3)
    - Bush, President George, 1989 (invitation) (Box 4, Folder F.4)
    - CBS, 1984-1990 (Box 9, Folder F.3-4)
    - CBS Sports, 1988 (Box 9, Folder F.5)
    - CPB, 1988 (Box 9, Folder F.6)
    - CalTech, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder F.7)
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1986 (Box 9, Folder F.8)
    - Cerf, Bennett, 1990 (Box 9, Folder F.9)
    - Charles A. Dana Foundation, 1990 (Box 10, Folder F.1)
    - Clurman, Richard, 1988-1991 (Box 10, Folder F.2)
    - Columbia Students, 1989 (Box 10, Folder F.3)
    - Columbia University, 1960-1990 (Box 10, Folder F.4)
    - Committee on the Constitution, 1991 (Box 10, Folder F.5)
    - Cox, Archibald, 1968 (Box 10, Folder F.6)
    - Dartmouth College, 1986 (Box 15, Folder F.1)
    - Duke Endowment, 1988 (Box 15, Folder F.2)
    - DuPont Awards Foundation, 1980-1988 (Box 15, Folder F.3)
    - East-West Center, 1989 (Box 17, Folder F.1)
    - Edward Klauber Memorial Fund, 1967-1968, (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder F.2-3)
    - Edward Klauber Memorial Fund, 1967-1968, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder F.1-2)
    - Eisenhower, President Dwight, 1965 (Box 18, Folder F.3)
    - Elliot, Marsha, 1988 (Box 18, Folder F.4)
    - Equitable Life Assurance Society, 1985-1986 (Box 18, Folder F.5)
    - Erbure, Robert, 1983-1984 (Box 18, Folder F.6)
    - Fain, Norman, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder F.4)
    - FCC Article Reactions, 1975 (Box 19, Folder F.5)
    - Fleming, Robbin, 1984-1988 (Box 19, Folder F.6)
    - Ford, Gerald, 1983-1987 (Box 19, Folder F.7)
    - Foreman, Sir Denis, 1984-1987 (Box 19, Folder F.8-9)
    - Fox, Joe, 1981 (Box 23, Folder F.1)
    - Friendly, Ruth, 1960-1992 (Box 67)
    - Gannett Center for Media Studies, 1987-1990 (Box 23, Folder F.2-3)
    - Gaylin, Willard, 1985 (Box 23, Folder F.4)
    - Gold, Robert, 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder F.5)
    - Graff, Henry F., 1990 (Box 23, Folder F.6)
    - Granada Television, 1982-1987 (Box 23, Folder F.7)
    - Greene, Sir Hugh, 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder F.8)
    - Gutman, Howard, 1984 (Box 23, Folder F.9)
    - Hatch, Orin, 1985-1986 (Box 26, Folder F.5)
    - Heard, Alexander, 1984-1987 (Box 26, Folder F.6)
    - Hearst Corporation, 1986 (Box 26, Folder F.7)
    - Holocaust Documentary, 1978 (Box 26, Folder F.8)
    - Holocaust Memorial Center, 1988 (Box 26, Folder F.9)
    - Indiana Civil Liberties Union, 1973 (Box 30, Folder F.4)
    - Interchurch Center, 1990 (Box 30, Folder F.5)
    - Iselin, John, 1985 (Box 30, Folder F.6)
    - KQED, 1986-1987 (Box 32, Folder F.1)
    - Kaufmann, Irving, 1985 (Box 32, Folder F.2)
    - Kendrich, Alexander, 1969 (Box 32, Folder F.3)
    - Konner, Joan, 1988-1992 (Box 32, Folder F.4)
    - Lab School of Washington, 1990 (Box 35, Folder F.3)
    - Lippman, Walter, 1967 (Box 35, Folder F.4)
    - Major, Lee, 1979-1980 (Box 39, Folder F.6)
    - McGraw Hill, 1987 (Box 39, Folder F.7)
    - McNeil/Lehrer News Hour, 1985 (Box 38, Folder F.1)
    - Miller, Arthur, 1988-1990 (Box 38, Folder F.2)
    - Minow, Newton, 1983 (Box 38, Folder F.3)
    - National Public Broadcasting Archives, 1991-1992 (Box 42, Folder F.7)
    - National Constitution Center, 1988-1991, (3 Folders) (Box 43, Folder F.1-3)
    - Nesson, Charles, 1984-1990 (Box 43, Folder F.4)
    - Oaks, Dallin, 1983-1984 (Box 45, Folder F.1)
    - Ogletree, Charles, 1988-1991 (Box 45, Folder F.2)
    - PBS, 1984-1991, (3 Folders) (Box 45, Folder F.8-10)
    - Paley, William, 1964-1965 (Box 45)
    - Pogrebin, Abigail, 1990 (Box 46, Folder F.1)
    - Powell, Lewis, 1987 (Box 46, Folder F.2)
    - Robinson, Dan, 1983-1985 (Box 48, Folder F.7)
    - Rosen, Jack, 1972 (includes caricature of Friendly) (Box 49, Folder F.1)
    - Sack, Robert, 1984 (Box 51, Folder F.5)
    - Sandberg, Carl, undated (Box 51, Folder F.6)
    - Schneider, John (CBS), 1965-1966 (Box 51, Folder F.7)
    - Schmidt, Benno, 1971-1986 (Box 51, Folder F.8)
    - Stanton, Frank, 1964 (Box 51, Folder F.9)
    - Stanton, Frank, 1964-1966 (Box 52, Folder F.1-4)
    - Stein, Robert, 1982-1987 (Box 52, Folder F.5)
    - Stewart, Potter, 1983-1984 (Box 52, Folder F.6)
    - Sucherman, Stewart, 1990-1991 (Box 52, Folder F.7)
    - Syracuse--Grove Press, 1975 (Box 52, Folder F.8)
    - Times Mirror, 1986 (Box 59, Folder F.4)
    - University of Utah, 1986 (Box 61, Folder F.1)
    - U.S. Holocaust Memorial Council, 1981-1987 (Box 61, Folder F.2)
    - WNET, 1986-1991 (Box 61, Folder F.8)
    - Wiseman, Frederick, 1988 (Box 62, Folder F.1)
    - Weinberger, Casper, 1984 (Box 62, Folder F.2)
- Series II: Writing, 1940-1996
  Friendly produced dozens of articles and speeches, as well as several books. Although his work covers many topics, he was especially interested in free speech, the history and impact of television, and the role of ethics in government, business, law, and journalism. This series consists primarily of drafts, research notes, and correspondence with editors and colleagues
  - Subseries II.1: Articles, 1940-1993
    Friendly's short articles on media and ethics appeared frequently in popular magazines and newspapers, particularly The New York Times and The Washington Post. He was also called upon to write book reviews and prefaces for books on radio and televison history. This subseries includes drafts and research notes for a number of his articles, filed alphabetically by title.
    - "After the Westmoreland Case," 1985 (Box 68, Folder F.1-2)
    - "Anecdota Orienta," undated (Box 68, Folder F.3)
    - "Asleep at the Switch of the Wired City," 1970 (Box 68, Folder F.4)
    - "ATC's Aerial Supply Route to China," circa 1940 (Box 68, Folder F.5)
    - "A Bench-mark for the World"--50th Anniversary of BBC, 1972 (Box 68, Folder F.6)
    - Broadcasting Essay, undated (Box 68, Folder F.7)
    - "By Television's Flickering Light: The Last Twenty-Five Years," 1990 (Box 68, Folder F.8)
    - Review of Close Encounters by Michael Wallace, 1984 (Box 68, Folder F.9)
    - "A Crime and its Aftershock," 1976, (3 Folders) (Box 68, Folder F.10-12)
    - "A Crime and its Aftershock," 1976 (Box 69, Folder F.1)
    - "Dear Jack Gould, They Say You Are Retired," 1972 February 27 (Box 69, Folder F.2)
    - Review of Emergence of a Free Press by Leonard Levy, 1985 February 24 (Box 69, Folder F.3)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica Articles, 1971-1972 (Box 69, Folder F.4)
    - "Ethics is When No One Else is Watching!," 1991 (Box 69, Folder F.5)
    - "Fifty Years Later: The Minnesota Case that Shaped the Constitution," 1981 (Box 69, Folder F.6)
    - "From Intense Tennis in Stockbridge to Intensive Care at BMC," 1978 (Box 69, Folder F.7)
    - "Funds, Pluralism, and the Real Light at the End of the Tube," 1970 (Box 69, Folder F.8)
    - "Gays, Privacy, and a Free Press," 1990 April 8, (2 Folders) (Box 69, Folder F.9-10)
    - "General Patton and the Chinese," circa 1940s (Box 69, Folder F.11)
    - "Here Lies Richard Nixon," undated (Box 69, Folder F.12)
    - "Imperial Media," undated (Box 69, Folder F.13)
    - Review of Make No Law by Anthony Lewis, 1991 (Box 69, Folder F.14)
    - "A Man Who Had Soul," 1970 August 24 (Box 69, Folder F.15)
    - Preface to Book Of Boundless Domain by Michael I. Sovern, 1993 (Box 69, Folder F.16)
    - Review of On the Firing Line by William Buckley, Jr., undated (Box 69, Folder F.17)
    - Response to Scientific American Article, "Opium, Cocaine, and Marijuana in American History," 1991 August 29 (Box 69, Folder F.18)
    - Preface to Book Presidential Television, 1973 (Box 69, Folder F.19)
    - Review of Prime Time: The Life of Edward R. Murrow by Alexander Rendrick, 1969 (Box 69, Folder F.20)
    - "Reforming American Government," undated (Box 69, Folder F.21)
    - "Reminiscences and Observations," undated (Box 69, Folder F.22)
    - Rip-Saw Article for Near vs. Minnesota Case, 1980 (Box 69, Folder F.23)
    - "Some Sober Second Thoughts on Vice President Agnew," circa 1970 (Box 70, Folder F.1)
    - "Sullivan Reconsidered: Time to Return to the Central Meaning of the First Amendment," 1992 (Box 70, Folder F.2)
    - "Tempest in a NewsBox," undated (Box 70, Folder F.3)
    - "TV at the Turning Point," 1971 (Box 70, Folder F.4)
    - "Twenty-Five Years Ago...," 1990 December 21 (Box 70, Folder F.5)
    - "The Unselling of 'The Unselling of the Pentagon,'" 1971 March 3 (Box 70, Folder F.6-7)
    - Review of "The Untended Gate," undated (Box 70, Folder F.8)
    - "A Valuable Lesson from 'Little Red Riding Hood,'" 1980 September 21 (Box 70, Folder F.9)
    - "Was Trust Betrayed?"--Review of The Journalist and the Murderer by Janet Malcolm, 1990 February 25, (2 Folders) (Box 70, Folder F.10-11)
    - "Watching the Watchdog," 1990 (Box 70, Folder F.12)
    - "What is Fair on the Air," 1975 March 30 (Box 71, Folder F.1)
    - "William S. Paley: The Super Producer," 1963 July 30 (Box 71, Folder F.2)
    - Untitled "Carnegie Piece," 1967 (Box 71, Folder F.3)
    - Untitled "Communications Paper," 1980 (Box 71, Folder F.4)
    - Untitled draft on Controversy and TV, undated (Box 71, Folder F.5)
  - Subseries II.2: Books, 1967-1984 (Box 71)
    This subseries holds materials relating to Friendly’s four published books, as well as one unpublished manuscript, The Mole, the Judge and the Rule of Law, which reflected on the controversial court case British Steel Company vs. Granada Television. Materials are arranged alphabetically by title and include heavily annotated drafts, research notes, and occasional book reviews
    - The Constitution: That Delicate Balance
      - Drafts (3 Folders), 1984 (Box 71, Folder F.6-8)
      - Clippings and Notes, 1984 (Box 71, Folder F.9)
      - Book Reviews, 1984 (Box 71, Folder F.10)
      - Due to Circumstances Beyond Our Control
      - Drafts, 1975 (Box Box 72-75)
      - Research Notes, 1975 (Box Box 75-77)
      - Good Guys, Bad Guys, and the First Amendment
      - Drafts, 1967 (Box Box 77-80)
      - Research Notes and FCC Information, 1967 (Box 80-82)
      - Book Reviews, 1967 (Box 82)
      - Minnesota Rag
      - Drafts, 1980-1982 (Box Box 82-87)
      - Research Notes, 1980-1982 (Box 88)
      - The Mole, The Judge and the Rule of Law
      - Drafts, 1980 (Box Box 89-91)
      - Research Notes, 1980 (Box 91)
  - Subseries II.3: Speeches, 1964-1996